<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<index version="1" name="foxAsteria-Reaper-Scripts">
  <category name="Arrangement">
    <reapack name="ReaRanger_fA.lua" type="script" desc="ReaRanger fA - Realtime Region List Editor">
      <version name="0.7.28" author="foxAsteria" time="2026-06-17T16:24:55Z">
        <source main="true">https://github.com/Poofox/foxAsteria-Reaper-Scripts/raw/ad19b2c9e914e6bfffb084afb35f945f74f28aa3/ReaRanger_fA.lua</source>
        <changelog><![CDATA[v0.7.28 — Length/duration entry honours the Time/Beats toggle everywhere (was
seconds-only in three spots): the +Region length field, the gap field, and the
lane hover "len" readout. Values stay seconds internally.

v0.7.27 — CONTENT-COMPLETE moves. New carry_content() primitive: reordering a
region or free-moving it on the lane now carries the media items AND the track
automation (envelope points) AND normal markers AND tempo/timesig markers in the
span — not just the audio items. 100% deterministic set-absolute (no native
ripple, pref/timebase-independent). NOTE on beats-timebase projects: moving
tempo markers re-warps beat-anchored content (REAPER's anchoring) — flat-tempo
and time-timebase projects are unaffected.

v0.7.26 — Ctrl+drag-DUPLICATE on the lane: hold Ctrl and drag a region to clone
it (marker + the media items in its span) to the drop point. Respects the
Insert/Lanes toggle. Items cloned via state chunk with regenerated GUIDs.

v0.7.25 — Title-band text readability: app-name and info/stats line both use the
near-white title color.

v0.7.19 — Ship release. Realtime region-list editor / lite arranger:
- Reorder regions (list or lane) and the media content moves with them.
- Insert gaps (single-click +Gap, double-click to type exact length).
- Per-digit time drag (grab minutes / seconds / ms independently; Ctrl = fine).
- Lane drag to reorder, drag edges to resize; beats/time toggle.
- In-place rename (double-click), custom color picker per region.

BETA: actively developed — expect rough edges. A per-session telemetry log is
written under REAPER's Data/ReaRanger/ for diagnosing moves.
Requires ReaImGui (install via ReaPack: ReaTeam Extensions).]]></changelog>
      </version>
      <metadata>
        <description><![CDATA[ReaRanger fA is a lightweight region-list arranger for REAPER. It shows your project regions as an editable list plus an overview lane; reordering a region physically moves the content under it — media items, track automation, normal markers, and tempo/timesig markers all travel together. Inserting a gap opens silence and slides later audio right. Per-digit time dragging, in-place rename, custom per-region colors, and a beats/time display toggle. Built by foxAsteria with Claude.

BETA — actively developed. A per-session telemetry log is written under REAPER's Data/ReaRanger/ folder to help diagnose move behavior.

Requires the ReaImGui extension (install via ReaPack from the ReaTeam Extensions repository).]]></description>
        <link rel="website">https://github.com/Poofox/foxAsteria-Reaper-Scripts</link>
      </metadata>
    </reapack>
  </category>
</index>
